<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LOOP Walker</string>

    <string name="title_walks">Walks</string>
    <string name="title_maps">Maps</string>
    <string name="title_myprofile">My Profile</string>

    <string name="loop1_description">This section starts at Erith station and heads south to finish close to Bexley station in the historic village of Old Bexley. It offers easy walking, mainly level on riverside paths, with a few short climbs. Paths beside the rivers can, at times, be muddy. There are cafes and pubs at many places along the way and you can picnic at Hall Place.</string>
    <string name="loop2_description">This section offers a very green and mostly easy route through the suburbs of southeast London. It starts in Old Bexley High Street, close to Bexley station. At first, it shares the route of the Cray Riverway through sports grounds and open areas, then beside the River Cray in Foots Cray Meadows, possibly one of the most charming sections of the whole London Loop. There are cafes and pubs at Sidcup Place and Petts Wood, where there are also public toilets. </string>
    <string name="loop3_description">This section of the LOOP passes through attractive countryside with strong links to Charles Darwin who described the countryside around the village of Downe as \'the extreme verge of the world\'. The walking is generally easy, but with a few longish, steep slopes, stiles and kissing gates and some small flights of steps. Much of it is through commons, parks and along tracks. There are cafes and pubs at many places along the way and you can picnic at High Elms, where there are also public toilets. The walk starts at Jubilee Country Park and finishe at Hayes station. There are several bus routes along this walk.</string>
    <string name="loop4_description">This well-wooded section has a fair amount of climbing, rewarded by some splendid views. The route also passes through commons, gardens and nature reserves. There are numerous pubs and you can picnic at many places along the way. There are public toilets and a restaurant at Addington Hills.</string>
    <string name="loop5_description">This very attractive section starts just outside Greater London. It features, in \'quick succession\', four commons - Riddlesdown, Kenley Common, Coulsdon Common and Farthing Downs - the latter providing a long ridge walk with fine views and grazing cattle. Other points of interest include Happy Valley with its rare yellow rattle plant and Devilsden Wood. It is mostly on level ground with three long climbs (two of them very steep with steps). The terrain is mainly rough tracks, footpaths and grassy fields. There are pubs and cafes at Hamsey Green, Godstone Road, Kenley Aerodrome, Coulsdon Common and Coulsdon South and an occasional kiosk at Farthing Downs. There are public toilets at Farthing Downs. </string>
    <string name="loop6_description">This section starts with a long, steady climb through residential roads in Coulsdon and Clockhouse, but after that the route is almost entirely level in attractive countryside, with some fine views towards London. You pass the distinctive black weatherboard houses of the smallholdings on the Little Woodcote Estate, then open fields lead to The Oaks Park, with its cafe, toilets a nd nature trail. This is easy walking on mostly level ground. There are some stiles and kissing gates and only Oaks Park is suitable for wheelchairs and pushchairs. At Banstead station you can carry on to Section seven to Bourne Hall Park, Ewell. </string>
    <string name="loop7_description">Although one of the shortest and perhaps the least green sections of the LOOP, section seven does have much of interest. This is easy walking on mostly level ground, but with a few long slopes from Sandy Lane to Holmwood Road and two flights of steps. Sections suitable for the less mobile and pushchairs are Warren Farm and Nonsuch Park. Points of interest on this walk are Warren Farm, which is a Woodland Trust Reserve, Nonsuch Park, Nonsuch Mansion, Bourne Hall Park and the old village jail at Ewell. There is a cafe and toilets at Nonsuch Mansion and other places to eat along the way. At Bourne Hall Park you can carry on to Section eight to Kingston upon Thames. </string>
    <string name="loop8_description">The waters and woods of this section have something for everyone; you\'ll see scenery that inspired Pre-Raphaelite painters, overhanging willows and the gentle curves of the river. This is an easy walk on mostly level ground. The paths alongside the Hogsmill can be muddy. The section from Berrylands station to Kingston is suitable for the less mobile and pushchairs. There are stations near the route at Maldon Manor and Berrylands; all the trains are to and from Waterloo. Points of interest on this walk are the Hogsmill River, the Saxon Coronation Chair and the medieval Clattern Bridge. There are cafes and pubs at both ends of the route, but no public toilets. </string>
    <string name="loop9_description">This section of the LOOP features easy walking with some extensive green stretches on entirely level ground, mostly on grass and rough footpaths. There is one stile. There are cafes and pubs along the route. Points of interest on this section are Bushy Park, the Diana Fountain, Waterhouse Woodland Gardens, Crane Park, the Shot Tower and Hounslow Heath. </string>
    <string name="loop10_description">Despite the heavy traffic in this area and the multitude of planes arriving and leaving Heathrow, this shorter LOOP section includes much pleasant walking. It is entirely on level ground, except for a spiral ramp onto the firm canal towpath. There is also a narrow rough path beside the River Crane. Much of the route runs alongside the River Crane and a canal towpath taking in the former grounds of the Earl of Berkeley\'s mansion and the lush meadows of Cranford Park. There are pubs and cafes at Hayes, and public toilets at Cranford Park Information Centre. </string>
    <string name="loop11_description">The walk starts at Hayes and Harlington station (with trains from Paddington) and finishes at Uxbridge on the Tube; along the route there is a station at West Drayton on the line from Paddington. Points of interest on this walk are the Grand Union Canal and Little Britain Lake. There are cafes and pubs along the route, but no public toilets. </string>
    <string name="loop12_description">This section follows the Grand Union Canal for most of the way. It is dominated by water which makes it the bluest section of the London LOOP. There are lots of interesting things to see along the way including locks, narrow boats, canalside pubs and a tearoom. This is an easy walk on mainly firm and level towpaths. There are three small canal bridges to cross and one short stretch on rough track. The walk starts at Uxbridge tube station and finishes at Harefield with buses which return to Uxbridge station; mid-route there are buses at South Harefield. There is a cafe and public toilets at Colne Park Visitor Centre and other cafes and pubs along the way.</string>
    <string name="loop13_description">This is a very pleasant section keeping away from settlements, going through remote countryside and luxuriant woodland. It is an easy walk mainly on rough paths, tracks and grass. There is a steep hill soon after the start, otherwise the path is fairly level with some gentle slopes. The walk starts at Harefield West, which can be reached by bus from Uxbridge station and finishes at Moor Park station on the Metropolitan Line. The route goes away from the Grand Union Canal that the previous two sections followed and goes through parks and wood. Highlights are the ancient Park and Bishop\'s Woods and the Ye Olde Greene Manne pub with its connections to Dick Turpin and Moor Park Mansion. There are cafes and pubs at Harefield West, Woodcock Hill and Batchworth Heath, but no public toilets until Moor Park. </string>
    <string name="loop14_description">This is an easy walking, very green and quite short LOOP section through woodland with little road-walking. It crosses farmland around the community of Pinnerwood, where you walk between charming cottages with well-kept ponds and lawns. Walking is mainly on rough paths, tracks and grass, which may be muddy at times. There are two stiles and four kissing gates and some short steep slopes, but generally gently undulating. The walk starts close to Moor Park station on the Metropolitan line and ends at Hatch End station with trains to Euston and Harrow and Wealdstone. The highlights of this walk are the Old Furze Wood, the 97 hectare Oxhey Wood nature reserve and Pinnerwood House, home of the famous Victorian author Bulwer-Lytton. On clear days there are some great views. There are public toilets at the start at Moor Park, and pubs and cafes at Moor Park and Hatch End. </string>
    <string name="loop15_description">This longer section follows the green belt on the fringe of Greater London crossing the Hertfordshire border several times. It goes through picturesque woodland and pastures, and is easy walking on mostly level ground with a few longish slopes and some field edge, farmland and woodland path walking. The highlights of this walk are Grim\'s Ditch (the mansion of W S Gilbert, of Gilbert and Sullivan fame - now Grim\'s Dyke Hotel), Bentley Priory with its World War II connections, and the Roman Watling Street. There are many stiles and kissing gates. The sections more suitable for the less mobile and pushchairs include Bentley Priory Open Space, Grove Fields and Aldenham Country Park. The walk starts at Hatch End (or from Hatch End station on the line from Euston) and ends at Elstree and Borehamwood station with trains to King\'s Cross and Luton. There is a cafe and public toilets at Aldenham Country Park, as well as pubs along the way. </string>
    <string name="loop16_description">This is the longest section of the London LOOP and is very pleasant despite a high proportion of road walking, taking in some attractive open spaces and commons in North London. Points of interest are Dollis Brook, Moat Mount (site of the 1471 Battle of Barnet during the Wars of the Roses) and Livingstone Cottage, where the famous explorer of that name lived in the 1850s. It\'s mainly level walking on rough paths, tracks and grass. There is one longish steep ascent and several fairly gentle ascents and descents. There are two stiles. There are pubs and cafes at Borehamwood, Barnet, Hadley and Cockfosters and public toilets at Barnet and Trent Park. There are few opportunities to leave this section of the LOOP, but it does pass very close to High Barnet station on the northern line, about two-thirds of the way round. </string>
    <string name="loop17_description">This is a long and rural section through an area alive with history. It goes by Trent Park, once the home of the Sassoon family, whose mansion across the lake is now part of Middlesex University, through the farmland of Enfield Chase and Hilly Fields Park and the Forty Hall Estate. There are several gentle ups and downs, and two high-stepped footbridges. The walk is mostly on rough paths, tracks and grassland, and there are five stiles. Some sections are suitable for the less mobile and for pushchairs, these include Trent Park, Forty Hall and Albany Park. There are pubs and cafes at Trent Park, Forty Hall, Clay Hill, Turkey Street and Enfield Lock, and public toilets at both ends of Trent Park and at Forty Hall. There is a National Rail station at Turkey Street and several bus routes along the way. This section ends at the footbridge over the Brook near Enfield Lock Station - not Enfield Lock itself. The lock itself can be found in Section 18 of the LOOP.</string>
    <string name="loop18_description">You\'re in green surroundings nearly all the way in this shorter section, beside the gentle current of London\'s waterways and through the wooded countryside. The terrain is mostly flat but a stiff climb into the Sewardstone Hills is rewarded with a magnificent view across north London. In Epping Forest you encounter another fairly steep climb up to Hawk Wood. The surface is mostly rough paths, tracks and grass; there are nine stiles. The section from Enfield Lock station to Swan and Pike Pool is suitable for the less mobile and pushchairs. Points of interest are Enfield Small Arms Factory, King George V Reservoir, Sewardstone Marsh Nature Reserve, the Scout Headquarters at Gilwell Park and Yardley and Hawk Woods. There are cafes and pubs at Enfield Lock, Sewardstone Road and Chingford, and public toilets at Chingford. National Rail services run from Enfield Lock and Chingford, and there are several bus routes along the way. This section starts at the footbridge over Turkey Brook near Enfield Lock station - not at Enfield Lock itself. </string>
    <string name="loop19_description">This shortish section will take you through the open spaces of Epping Forest and the meadows of the Roding Valley Meadows Nature Reserve. It’s easy walking but some parts of Epping Forest may be muddy. There is one gentle climb near the start and part of the route is on pavements and tarmac paths. Some parts of Roding Valley Meadows Local Nature area are accessible for the less mobile and pushchairs. The highlights are Queen Elizabeth’s Hunting Lodge and the magnificent ancient oaks in Epping Forest. There are pubs and cafes at Chingford,Epping New Road, High Road, Woodford Green, Loughton Way and Chigwell. Public toilets are at Chingford, Linder’s Field Nature Reserve and Roding Valley Recreation Area. There are underground stations at Buckhurst Hill, Debden and Chigwell and buses along the way. </string>
    <string name="loop20_description">This section is one of the most rural sections of the whole LOOP, being almost entirely in open country, woodland or undulating farmland. Points of interest are the country parks at Hainault with its lake and Havering Country Park with the pleasant village of Havering-atte-Bower, from which the London borough takes its name, at the end. The terrain is generally level with some gentle slopes and six stiles. It is mostly on rough paths or tracks and on grass; some fields may be ploughed. There are pubs and cafes at Chigwell, Chigwell Row, Havering-atte-Bower, and public toilets at Hainault Forest Country Park and Havering-atte-Bower. There are tube stations at Chigwell and Grange Hill and buses along the route. The bus service to and from Havering-atte-Bower is infrequent and doesn\'t run on Sundays - please check the timetable before travelling. Other buses are available miles from the end of this section of the LOOP. </string>
    <string name="loop21_description">From the attractive village of Havering-atte-Bower this section first passes through high-lying, undulating farmland, to reach Noak Hill. It then follows a narrow green strip through the suburb of Harold Hill, which lies beside Carter\'s and Paine\'s Brooks. These streams flow into the River Ingrebourne, which itself joins the Thames at Rainham Creek. This section has generally fairly level walking, mostly on rough paths, tracks and grass and there are five stiles. The section through Central Park is suitable for people with limited mobility and pushchairs. There are pubs at Havering-atte-Bower, Noak Hill and Harold Wood, and public toilets at Havering-atte-Bower. There is a National Rail station at Harold Wood, and buses serving Havering-atte-Bower, Noak Hill, Harold Hill and Harold Wood. </string>
    <string name="loop22_description">This fairly short section goes through Pages Wood - a superb new community woodland of 74 hectares, as well as other woods, the riverside of the Ingrebourne and expansive pasture. The highlights include Upminster Windmill and the wooden artworks in Pages Wood. The terrain is almost completely level with one or two short gentle slopes. It\'s mostly on footpaths, tracks and grass, often with rough surfaces. There is a more accessible section from Harold Wood to Hall Lane. There are pubs and cafes at Harold Wood and Upminster Bridge. There are buses at Southend Arterial Road, Hall Lane and Wingletye Lane if needed. </string>
    <string name="loop23_description">This section starts with the fascinating Upminster Windmill and generally follows the River Ingrebourne. You walk through Hornchurch Country Park which has gone through several phases as a farm, military airfield, gravel quarry and rubbish tip, until its acquisition in 1980 by the local authority. The terrain is almost completely level with tarmac or firm gravel paths and there are no stiles, so all this section is very accessible. There are pubs at Upminster Bridge, Hacton Lane, Rainham Road, Rainham village, and cafes and toilets at Rainham. There is also a toilet next to Upminster Bridge station. </string>
    <string name="loop24_description">This final section of the LOOP starts at Rainham station and continues to the end of the LOOP at Purfleet. The first part is mainly on roads, but soon meets the Thames with views across the river to Erith, where Section 1 of the London LOOP begins. Points of interest are the ancient river ferry crossing point, Rainham, Wennington and Aveley Marshes, the Second World War concrete barges and the RSPB visitor\'s centre. The walk is almost entirely level, with one or two short gentle slopes, on mostly hard surface with some grass. There are no stiles but there are some high steps. There is access for wheelchairs and pushchairs from the Coldharbour Riverside car park to the RSPB visitor\'s centre. There is a cafe with toilets at the RSPB site, and pubs and cafes at Rainham and Purfleet, but no public toilets. Public transport is only available at Rainham and Purfleet, so be prepared to do the full five miles of this section.</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
</resources>
